Industrial Designers Society of America (IDSA) Records
Industrial Designers Society of America (IDSA) Records
- General files
  - International
    - General, 1970 -- Council of Societies, 23 folders (Box 67)
    - Council of Societies, 2 folders (Box 68)
    - Countries
      - Africa -- France, 1958, 26 folders (Box 68)
      - France, 1963 -- Great Britain, 1965, 29 folders (Box 69)
      - Great Britain, 1965 -- Italy, 1964, 34 folders (Box 70)
      - Italy, 1961 -- Philippines, 1965, 39 folders (Box 71)
      - Poland -- Yugoslavia, 13 folders (Box 72)
    - Foreign design groups -- trade fairs, 19 folders (Box 72)
  - Intra-professional, 1967-1970; 4 folders (Box 72)
  - Job resumes, 1957-1958; 2 folders (Box 72)
  - Job seekers, inquiries, and placement, 4 folders (Box 72)
  - Joint Action, 1959-1960 (Box 73)
  - Labor, U.S. Department of (Box 73)
  - "Lahti" studies (Box 73)
  - Leases, offices, 3 folders (Box 73)
  - Legal, 1968-1971; 6 folders (Box 73)
  - Liaison, 1963-1964; 3 folders (Box 73)
  - Library, 1953-1970; 3 folders (Box 73)
  - Licensing, 1969; 2 folders (Box 73)
  - Logo (Box 73)
  - Long Island Railroad (Box 73)
  - Long range policy (Box 73)
  - Mailing lists, 1971; 3 folders (Box 73)
  - Machine design (Box 73)
  - Management (Box 73)
  - Management aids (Box 73)
  - Marketing (Box 73)
  - Material on loan, 1958-1962; 2 folders (Box 73)
  - Materials (Box 73)
  - Materials suppliers (Box 73)
  - Membership
    - General -- Applications, general, 14 folders (Box 73)
    - Applications, general, 14 folders (Box 74)
    - Applications
      - General -- Dike, Roy Wesley, 49 folders (Box 75)
      - Deskey, Donald -- Gunther, Harst, 35 folders (Box 76)
      - Gustafson, F. Malcolm -- Lynxwiler, Thomas L. D., 40 folders (Box 77)
      - L--U, V, W, 50 folders (Box 78)
      - Rejected (Box 79)
    - Biographies, 1952 -- Expansion, 1971, 41 folders (Box 79)
    - Information -- Lists, 40 folders (Box 80)
    - Lists -- Student, 26 folders (Box 81)
  - Merchandise mart (Box 81)
  - Merchandising (Box 81)
  - Merger, 1965; 7 folders (Box 81)
  - Metropolitan survey (Box 81)
  - Model makers (Box 82)
  - Motivation research (Box 82)
  - Name for a new society (Box 82)
  - National Alliance of Art and Industry, Inc. (Box 82)
  - National Committee for Effective Design Legislation (Box 82)
  - National Council on the Arts, 1967-1970; 7 folders (Box 82)
  - National defense (Box 82)
  - Narional Design Center (Box 82)
  - National Institute for Commercial and Trade Organization Executives (Box 82)
  - National Industrial Conference Board (Box 82)
  - National Office
    - General, 1956 -- President's Annual Report, 1964, 37 folders (Box 82)
    - President's Annual Report, 1965 - Vice President's Report, 1960, 32 folders (Box 83)
  - National reports (Box 83)
  - National Safety Council (Box 83)
  - National Society for Decorative Design (Box 83)
  - National Society for Study of Communication (Box 83)
  - National Society of Interior Designers (Box 83)
  - New York State Council on the Arts (Box 83)
  - New York State Personnel Management Association (Box 83)
  - New York State Society of Professional Engineers (Box 83)
  - News/press clippings, 1957-1971; 21 folders (Box 84)
  - Newsletter
    - 1951-1954, 28 folders (Box 84)
    - 1955-1958, 39 folders (Box 85)
    - 1958-1961, 32 folders (Box 86)
    - 1961-1964, 43 folders (Box 87)
    - 1964-?, typescripts, 17 folders (Box 88)
  - Nominations and elections, 1968-1971; 5 folders (Box 88)
  - Non profit organizations (Box 88)
  - Obsolescence, 1956; 2 folders (Box 88)
  - Office routine, 2 folders (Box 88)
  - Office supplies, 2 folders (Box 89)
  - Organizational charts (Box 89)
  - Organizations, miscellaneous, 1970-1971; 4 folders (Box 89)
  - P.E.P., 1970 (Box 89)
  - Package Designers Council, 1969-1971; 4 folders (Box 89)
  - Package research conference (Box 89)
  - Packaging, 2 folders (Box 89)
  - Packaging Institute (Box 89)
  - Patents, 3 folders (Box 89)
  - Pending (Box 89)
  - Periodicals
    - General, 1955-1971; 21 folders (Box 89)
    - American Artist -- Journal, 35 folders (Box 90)
    - Journal -- U.S. Industrial Designe r, 41 folders (Box 91)
    - U.S. Industrial Designer -- Wall Street Journal, 16 folders (Box 92)
  - Personnel (Box 92)
  - Personnel classification (Box 92)
  - Photographic Society of America (Box 92)
  - Piracy and patents (Box 92)
  - Pitney Bowes postage machine (Box 92)
  - Placement, 3 folders (Box 92)
  - Plastics (Box 92)
  - Point of Purchase Advertising Institute (Box 92)
  - Postal license (Box 92)
  - Presentations
    - Films, 1967 -- Slides, 1971, 22 folders (Box 92)
    - Speeches
      - General -- Cambridge Lectures, 1949, 24 folders (Box 93)
      - Contini, Renato -- Whidden, R.H., 31 folders (Box 94)
  - Printing (Box 94)
  - Product engineering, 1957; 2 folders (Box 94)
  - Product identification (Box 94)
  - Product innovation (Box 94)
  - Product planning, 2 folders (Box 94)
  - Professionalism, 1958-1970; 6 folders (Box 94)
  - Program ideas, 1962-1963; 2 folders (Box 94)
  - Programs and samples, 3 folders (Box 94)
  - Progress reports
    - 1954-1960, 6 folders (Box 94)
    - 1960-1964, 9 folders (Box 95)
  - Project "Earning Power" (Box 95)
  - Proposal for modification of executive structure (Box 95)
  - Proposals re: alternate year design conference (Box 95)
  - Psychological Service Center (Box 95)
  - Public relations
    - General, 1953 -- Counsel, 1960, 22 folders (Box 95)
    - Council on Student Competition -- Publicity, 1970, 29 folders (Box 96)
  - Questionnaires and results (Box 96)
  - Reference file, 2 folders (Box 96)
  - Replies to questionnaires (Box 96)
  - Report on applications (Box 96)
  - Requests for Industrial Design Report (Box 96)
  - Research and development (Box 96)
  - Research and statistics
    - 1956-1960, 4 folders (Box 96)
    - 1960-1971, 14 folders (Box 97)
  - Research contracts (Box 97)
  - Research Institute of American (Box 97)
  - Research organizations (Box 97)
  - Researchers (Box 97)
  - Resumes (Box 97)
  - Review of SID activity (Box 97)
  - Roadside protection, 1969-1971; 3 folders (Box 97)
  - Safety, 1967-1971; 7 folders (Box 97)
  - Safety through design, 1966 (Box 97)
  - Sales management (Box 97)
  - Science Research Associates (Box 97)
  - Scientific Apparatus Makers Association (Box 97)
  - Secretarial service (Box 97)
  - Small Business Administration (Box 97)
  - Society of Business Advisory Professionals (Box 97)
  - Society of Industrial Artists, 1970 (Box 97)
  - Society of Plastics Engineers, 2 folders (Box 97)
  - Society of Plastics Industry (Box 97)
  - Society of Typographic Arts (Box 97)
  - Sources
    - 1955-1958, 3 folders (Box 97)
    - 1959-1969, 9 folders (Box 98)
  - Speakers, 1963-1971; 3 folders (Box 98)
  - Speakers' Bureau questionnaire, 1963 (Box 98)
  - Special Study Group, 1969-1970; 2 folders (Box 98)
  - Speculative Design (Box 98)
  - Standard employment agreement (Box 98)
  - Statistics, 1968-1969; 10 folders (Box 98)
  - Suggestions (Box 98)
  - Survey information, 5 folders (Box 98)
  - Symposiums
    - 1955-1963, 30 folders (Box 99)
    - 1964-1970, 8 folders (Box 100)
  - Table of organization, 1969-1971; 3 folders (Box 100)
  - Tape of library, 1969 (Box 100)
  - Technical Information System, 1970-1971; 2 folders (Box 100)
  - Trade and industry (Box 100)
  - Trade mark (Box 100)
  - Trade Mark Association (Box 100)
  - UNESCO (Box 100)
  - Umbrella Society, 1968 (Box 100)
  - United States Information Agency (Box 100)
  - United States Department of State (Box 100)
  - Veterans programs (Box 100)
  - Women in Design, 1970 (Box 100)
  - World Trade Center, 1970 (Box 100)
  - Year-end report, 1965-1971; 3 folders (Box 100)
  - Yearbook (Box 100)
  - Miscellaneous
    - General, 9 folders (Box 100)
    - Account book pages, 2 folders (Box 101)
    - Artwork and layouts, 3 folders (Box 101)
    - Certificate samples (Box 101)
    - Citations to industry (Box 101)
    - Design awards (Box 101)
    - Education Association studies reports (Box 101)
    - Journal proofs, 2 folders (Box 101)
    - Photographs, 38 folders (Box 102)
    - Photographs, 13 folders (Box 103)
    - Photographs, 22 folders (Box 104)
    - Photographs, 8 folders (Box 105)
    - Photographs, 3 folders (Box 106)
    - Promotional posters (Box 106)
    - Public relations packet, 2 folders (Box 106)
    - Report on member societies (Box 106)
    - Trademark samples (Box 106)
- Bound materials
  - Guest book, 1950 (Box 106)
  - Hotel register (Box 106)
  - Minutes books, 3 volumes (Box 106)
  - Minutes books, 3 volumes (Box 107)
  - Scrapbook (Box 107)
- Printed matter
  - Books
    - Design in America: Professional Practice for Designers, 5 volumes (Box 107)
  - Periodicals
    - American Designer -- Asia Notebook (Box 107)
    - Auburn University Bulletin -- Dateline (Box 108)
    - Dateline -- ICSID Report (Box 109)
    - ISCC Newsletter -- Mexico, 1968 Olympics (Box 110)
    - Mexico, 1968 Olympics (Box 111)
    - Mayen's Audio Visuals, pamphlets and bulletins (Box 112)
- Audio-visual material
  - Films, 2 folders (Box 113)
  - Slides, 3 folders, 7 packages (Box 113)
  - Tapes, 52 cassettes (Box 114)
  - Tapes, 40 reels (Box 115)
  - Tapes, 39 reels (Box 116)
  - Tapes, 37 reels (Box 117)
  - Television tape (Box 117)
- Memorabilia
  - Addressograph plates (Box 118)
  - Logo (Box 118)
  - Membership pins (Box 118)
  - Art work and layouts (Oversize 1)
  - Art work and layouts (Oversize 2)
  - Layouts and logos (Oversize 3)
  - Scrapbooks (Oversize 4)
  - Certificate and award samples (Oversize 5)
  - Journal proofs (Oversize 5)
  - Office forms (Oversize 5)
  - Miscellaneous drawings (Oversize 5)
  - Record album (Oversize 6)
  - Photographs (Oversize 6)
  - Photographs (Oversize 7)